Jake Zimmermann

T: 07545128394

E: jake zimmermann@hotmail.co.uk

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jake-zimmermann-66776339/

Github CV: https://github.com/JakeOtto



Personal Profile

Currently a student of Makers academy, studying Data Engineering whilst working as a WordPress developer for a few small-scale clients. Hard working with excellent problem-solving skills, strong observational/ collaborative skills, and quick hands-on learner, these skills have allowed me to pursue private projects both by myself and within a small team but have led me longing to develop a more substantial career in Data engineering. Previous experience in management roles has led to well-developed teamwork skills and good communicator habits, keen to help others in both work and community projects. Also, developing my ai interaction skills and a weekend greengrocer at Barnet market since 2007, which has led to great client facing communication skills and a fond, kind-hearted attitude to community interaction.

Experience

Proof Of Treasure – Private project

January 2022 - Present

- https://proofoftreasure.com
 - Developing programming skills with Chialisp (token transactions).
 - Building discord.py bots for community/staff interactions allowing more efficient team task management.
 - Public game creation methods as well as accuracy checks.
 - Working with a small developer team.

WordPress developer/teacher – Barnet Market

December 2021 - Ongoing

- https://barnet-market.co.uk
- Working with clients in person helping them develop skills for their own personal site maintenance and improvements.

WordPress developer – The After 30s Podcast

July 2020 - September 2021

- Managing, testing and optimising TA30s website using Google Analytics.
- Managing and implementing new content with WordPress CMS.
- Reporting bugs and suggesting improvements of the website to clients.
- Providing monthly website reports highlighting key metrics and on-site opportunities.
- Competitor research.
- On-site SEO.

IT support technician - London Metropolitan University

November 2017 - October 2019

- Managing accounts and providing first and second line support to the university students and faculty members.
- Working with system administration tools.
- Personal and group face to face support meetings.
- Working as part of a larger team.

Development Tools & Languages

Development tools

Visual Studio, Bluestacks, Eclipse, Glassfish, NetBeans, Slack, GitHub, Android Studio, GCP, React, Pytest, AWS, Docker

Languages used

Java, JavaScript, Python, CSS, PHP, Chialisp

Education

Makers Academy - Data engineering specialization

Sept 04 - January 14th, 2024

TDD and Object-Oriented-Programming focused in Python (agile, waterfall and free flowing development)

SQL and data processing

Data analysis and presenting insights

Data warehouse modelling

Charity/ Personal Experiences

- Teaching Math and PE Namanga Christian School, Kenya.
- Teaching, site construction Brothers of the Sacred Heart Zambia.
- Volunteer chef Paradise Parks kids' community centre.
- Development of personal languages, German, Mandarin.
- Mathematics revision centre popup mathematics revision centre, leaning business opening legalities and teaching skills.
- Coaching 2 years coaching in a popular e-sport, developing my confidence in making a
 viable career from a personal hobby. Further improving my communication skills through
 explaining concepts clearly and well to customers.
- London Youth Olympics three years Volleyball representative for Barnet, developing teamwork skills. Previously playing rugby for Saracen's youth teams too.
- Management roles
 - Restaurant manager Bufle, Rupert Street W1
 - Payrole, delegation, licencing, site management requirements, HR roles Duty manager Q.E. Girls sport centre
 - Delegation, rota/schedule management, staff teaching